eflorist.co.uk 2019-01-12

# Same Day Flower Delivery - Send Flowers Online Today!

Personal information is exactly what it is; yours. You share your information with Euroflorist because you would like to order something. But we can imagine that you would like to know why we ask for your personal information and what we do with it. We’re more than happy to tell you about this in here.

_1\. Data_

Euroflorist only uses personal data that you provide directly. This may be because of a product or service you have ordered.

We use the following data:

\- name and address of the shipping and delivery address;  
\- Phone number;  
\- Billing address;  
\- E-mail address;  
\- Payment information;  
\- IP address.

As you will understand, we also need the data for the delivery address. Of course you want your product to be delivered, either to your own address or to the address of the person you want to surprise.

You can also register as a customer first. In addition to your specified personal data, we also save the username you have chosen. This is useful because it will save you the trouble of having to enter your data every time. Our portal also allows you to enter and adjust these settings yourself.

_2\. Security_

We protect all information you provide us with the most modern techniques. After all, you do not want your data to suddenly be out on the street. We do not allow anyone that has nothing to do with your data access to it. Should it be necessary that we share the data with other companies (read why), then we require such a company to handle the data just as carefully as we do. Those companies may also only use the data for the purpose for which it was given.

_3\. Storage Periods_

We keep personal data as long as necessary to process your order. We then store the data for a maximum of two years for our own purposes (Purposes). The data will then be erased unless the law requires us to keep it longer. For example, the law obliges us to keep payment records for seven years.

_4\. Purposes_

We use the data we receive from you for different purposes. Here you can read which purposes that are.

Delivery of your order: Obviously we use the data for handling your order. If you order something you naturally want it to be delivered. It is also possible that we pass on the data to so-called 'third parties': all to ensure that your order is handled properly. You can read more about these 'third parties' here.

Advertising: We understand that you want to know about all the beautiful products we have. After giving us permission, you can receive notifications of this through e-mail or via social media.

Newsletter / SMS: It is also possible to register for our newsletter / SMS. This way you stay informed about our offers, promotions and news. Do you no longer wish to receive the newsletter / SMS? You can always unsubscribe via the link in any of our newsletters / SMS texts.

Questions: If you have a question about your order, then please visit our contact us page where you might find the answer or alternatively you can send a email or give us a call. Of course you can choose which information you send us. This data is only retained for as long as necessary to fully answer the question. After all, we want to help you as much as possible.

Location data: In order to help you as well as possible, it is sometimes necessary for us to collect your location data (GPS). When we need this information, we ask you for permission.

_5\. Third parties_

It is possible that we pass on the data to companies with which we partner with, so-called 'third parties'. These companies help us to properly handle your order.

5.1 Providers of navigation / mapping software such as Google Maps can store and process (location) data. It is also possible that the data is used by Google or Apple itself. We have no influence on this and refer you to the privacy statements of these companies if you require more information.

5.2 Whenever you place an order with us, or register as a customer, we will share the data linked to your username to third parties. We only do this if this is necessary for the execution of the agreement with us or if we are obliged to do so by law. For example, if we suspect that there is fraud or abuse of our webshop, we can pass on personal data to the competent authorities.

5.3 We want to make sure that you can use our website as optimally and personally as possible. We may use statistical services such as Google Analytics for this purpose. These services keep track of how you use our website. Of course we have made strict agreements with these companies. For example, the IP address is anonymised. Do you want to know which of these services we use exactly? [Click here](https://www.eflorist.co.uk/new-cookie-policy-cn40).

_6\. Third countries_

Some of the companies we work with are based in a country outside the European Union. The regulations in these countries do not always provide the same protection of personal data as European regulations. We have therefore entered into agreements with these companies in which they commit themselves to take appropriate safety measures. This way the data is always well protected.

_7\. Cookies_

We use cookies. Everything to ensure that our website works well and that you can enjoy shopping. Do you want to know more about the cookies and how to turn them off? [Click here](https://www.eflorist.co.uk/new-cookie-policy-cn40).

_8\. Third party websites_

Our website occasionally contains links to other websites. We have no influence on those other sites. We can not guarantee that these companies will handle the data just as safely as we do. We recommend that you first read the Privacy Statement of those sites before using them.

_9\. Changing the Privacy Statement_

In order to inform you as well as possible about the use of the data, it may be that we sometimes have to adjust this Privacy Statement. We advise you to regularly read this Privacy Statement so that you are aware of any changes.

_10\. Viewing, changing, deleting data or other questions?_

You can also send us a request to view, change, delete or transfer the data to you. For example, it is possible to check whether the data is correct. Do you want to know which data we use with your permission or do you want us to limit / stop the data processing? You can also request this. So you can always withdraw your permission for processing. If you want to know exactly how this works or have other questions about this Privacy Statement please let us know.

You can contact our data protection officer (DPO) for this. The DPO monitors and advises Euroflorist on the processing of personal data. You can reach the DPO by sending an e-mail to dpo@euroflorist.com or sending a letter to:

Euroflorist Europe B.V.  
to Artur Kaszak  
Hullenbergweg 250  
1101 BV Amsterdam

_11\. Complaints?_

Of course we are happy to help you if you have a complaint about our processing of the personal data. However, you can also file a complaint with the so-called '[Authority for Personal Data](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en)', which supervises the processing of personal data.
